Right, so welcome to
our deep dive planning
template. Let me give
you a rundown of
how it works and
then I'll introduce you
to the plan. So
a deep dive, what
is it? Well, it's
a 25 minute plus
video that basically should
lay out some kind
of system to get
a result. Now there
are other ways of
making these longer videos,
but this is the
one I'm going to
teach you. So this
is one of the
most profitable videos I
have ever made. Did
amazing reviews, did amazing
for sales. This is
Simon Squibb. He got
13 million views on
this two hour beast.
And then you can
see there's other types
of channels that make
these two that get
a lot of views
as well. So the
pros of a deep
dive are, they are
just amazing at warming
viewers up and turning
them into buyers. They're
also very good for
email signups and sales
so long as it's
executed well. But the
cons are probably one
of the best ways
to prove you're not
credible, because if you
take on a giant
process and try and
teach someone it, and
it doesn't really look
like you know what
you're talking about, people
are going to notice.
But also it's a
longer video. So it's
difficult to master. It's
difficult to keep people
engaged. We need to
put a lot more
work into the planning
to pull these off.
So who should make
these? Well, what I
would say is intermediate
creators and pros. So
if you are brand
new to YouTube, I
wouldn't jump into one
of these. I'd probably
try and get like
10, 20 videos under
your belt first. So
what kind of viewers
like watching these? Well,
they're viewer types who
love depth and they
love steps to get
a specific result. So
when you're doing your
research, you're going to
find that maybe some
of your previous outliers
were processed based. And
the AI showed you
the things that people
love about your content
is they like step
by step. So it's
great for those type
of viewers. It's great
for viewers who are
taking the topic seriously.
If you put an
hour long video up,
people who aren't bought
into the topic yet
aren't going to watch
it. But those who
are way more serious
about it are and
that's what makes it
good for converting views
to buyers, as well
as buyers who kind
of already know their
problem and they're actively
looking for a deeper
solution. So where are
these best used? If
you want to present
a clear system or
workflow, if you want
to teach strategy or
an execution that does
have many steps, that's
kind of it. Now,
the secret sauce to
these is a few
things. Firstly, what I
did in this one,
this is just an
outline of my previous
program. So what I
did was I just
kind of lay out
everything the program includes
and the order it's
in and then gave
like one little bit
of nugget of wisdom
per step rather than
everything deep. Now that's
kind of powerful because
it primes them for
your service too. The
next bit of secret
sauce to this is
let's say there are
100 things they need
to do to get
a result. We can't
give all of them
in a video. So
you want to simplify
it down to the
20 steps that are
the easiest to action.
They get the biggest
result. So basically the
highest leverage tasks. And
if you give them
that and they action
it and get a
result, it's going to
reflect well on you
and they're going to
come back to your
channel. The next thing
is you want to
use content that's not
just for you. So
you want to use
content that's client wins
as much as you
can. So in your
intro, when you set
up that you've got
this system, you need
to make it crystal
clear it worked and
look, here's who it
worked for and aren't
I amazing and look
at all these fantastic
results. And then when
you're transitioning between steps,
you might want to
set up the next
step like so. Okay,
so step five enabled
Jerry here to go
from £25 overweight to
winning a bikini modeling
competition.
And then you show
that result on screen.
So if you click
on it, you'll see
it. And then you're
going to go back
to the first step,
which is you're going
to watch and I'll
link to it later.
This video, within you
know, the first quarter
of it, you're going
to see how much
I'm like, this works.
This works. This works.
Look at this. Work's
proof proof proof. We
need to front load
proof in this. If
we're going to get
them to stick around
for a long time.
You also want to
tell your own relatable,
I've been their stories.
So if you run
this through skyscraper bot
and you ask it,
you know, what did
the viewers love about
it? You will see
that many of them
really liked the relatable
stories. I told out
my own struggle
the position the viewer
is in right now
and it just makes
you so much more
human you also need
to over deliver here
so my goal when
i created that video
was to make something
where people wrote i
can't believe this is
free and that's what
happened so one of
the things you need
to do in your
planning is take the
time to do that
now the next thing
to keep in mind
is the emotion logic
brick so the way
that we're gonna structure
deep dive is like
this intro proof i'll
show that means later
some emotion and then
the logical steps step
one step two step
three step four step
five if when you
are getting to a
step that is more
complex what you need
to do is get
into the habit of
going i know ed
didn't say emotion logic
emotion logic in this
brick but would it
be good to use
a story a metaphor
or a visual demo
to start off this
step to help people
explain and that's what
makes this kind of
black belt stuff because
you only really understand
what is super complex
to your viewers when
you've worked with them
for a long time
and you've had a
lot of conversations with
them so let's say
you've got 10 steps
in here and you're
just going to give
information here we might
say okay step five
is a complex one
i know people get
stuck on this i
also know people often
don't believe that this
step's powerful why don't
i tell a story
to start it to
show that it works
and then give the
step and then you
might get to step
15 and go do
you know what we
need a visual demo
here to simplify this
so the name of
the game is asking
do i need emotion
even if ed hasn't
said you have to
have it in the
logic brick now the
mistake to make here
is overwhelming viewers so
think of this as
a marathon for your
viewer to watch what
we can't do is
make them run up
a hill and struggle
to keep up in
the first few minutes
because you're going to
mentally exhaust them so
we need to make
sure that these videos
are just a master
class in simplification how
to reduce attention Book
Coleman the word mock
Testament by affordableness motion
paper and feature features
visual demos, frameworks, all
the things I've been
teaching you because we
need them to get
to the end. If
they get to the
end of these that
is where all the
buying power is unleashed.
So we need to
focus on simplification, not
getting them over confused
and not going and
talking over their head
with tons of information
that isn't well structured.
The next mistake is
no call to action.
I didn't make a
call to action in
this video other than
my email and it
still generated a quarter
of a million dollars.
That was a mistake.
I should have pitched
at the end of
this video because it's
basically kind of a
webinar. So if I
was doing a deep
dive, you know, and
it's 45 minutes long,
I would then pitch
quite aggressively at the
end and be like,
look, you've probably watched
this and gone, well,
there's way more to
it. I've been helping
people do this for
years. It's what I
do all day, every
day. You've seen all
the case studies, all
the wins I showed
you in here. If
you would like me
to help you with
this, just click the
link below. You can
learn more about how
I might be able
to do that. Something
like that, right? Doesn't
need to be much
more, but I wish
I'd pitched in mine.
And the next thing
is just not making
your information feel new,
easy, or inspiring. It
has to, has to
be a video that
ticks all of these
boxes for it to
really work well. All
right. So what's the
strategy for this video?
Well, firstly, you just
need to produce a
system, a framework, a
step -by -step something
to enable your viewer
to get a specific
result they want that
solves the problem you
know they care about.
You then want to
pitch a lead magnet
tailored to the video
or your offer in
there. So in mine,
I used an AI
bot as one of
the steps. And then
I said to the
viewers, you can have
this, get it below.
Now, the next thing
we're going to do
is the whole point
of this is conversions,
not views. Now I
know we want views
and conversions, but what
we want to do
is produce something that
warms people up and
get some over the
line. So if we
do this, we can
get views, we can
get emails, we can
get sales, we can
take control of the
views too. It's very
powerful. So what sort
of title should you
use for these videos?
You need to use
your own pattern bank
here. You can use
a lot of different
titles. You can use
keywords. You can use
a lot of different
to look at outliers
and things that have
worked on your own
channel. But if I
was just going to
give you a general
rule or guide here,
make the title very
clear. They're going to
get a specific result
following some steps and
avoid very general claims.
So we don't want
do this. It'll change
your life. It's the
exact process to go
from depressed to extreme
happiness in 90 days,
something like that. Right?
So how to X,
how to X in
Y times X. So
you can see how
to X in Y
times Y. So you
can see how to
X in Y times
Y. So you can
see how to X
in Y times Y.
So you can see
how to X in
Y times Y. How
I X step by
step, how I blew
up my business step
by step, right? So
that's a rough idea
for titles. Don't just
go and use them
because I've said they're
there. It's just an
example. Thumbnails. I would
highly recommend sticking to
a result, a cognitive
distance or a comparison
or curiosity thumbnail. So
a result, you simply
show the result of
your wants in the
thumbnail cognitive dissonance. You
challenge what they thought
to be true by
saying something like, don't
buy a house in
the thumbnail. Comparison is
a side -by -side
before and after. And
a curiosity is just
another way of making
them go how, what
or why. And we
really want them to
think that how, what
or why, because that's
what will get the
click. All right. So
let's go a bit
deeper on the framework.
So the way we're
going to structure the
deep dive is like,
so we have our
intro and what I
would recommend here is
if you're making a
video, it's going to
be like 45 minutes
long plus set more
up in your intro.
If you watch Simon
Squibb's two hour absolute
beast, he sets up
what's in his video
for about two minutes.
It's really annoying and
over the top. And
most people would have
skipped that. But what
I recommend doing is
setting up, maybe five
things because we want
to raise that tension
nice and high. Then
you have to provide
proof this works because
nobody is going to
sit around and listen
to any of this.
If there's no proof.
So once you set
up that intro, it's
like his proof, it
works. Here's a client
who did this. Here's
someone who went from
X to Y, like
get as much in
as you can. Don't
labor it for too
long, but talking like
30 seconds of proof
here, then we have
the emotion break. So
there's lots of different
ways of doing this,
but my preferred method
is this call it
old way. New way.
What we do is
we. Shit. All I
want to do is
I want to do
this. I want to
do this. I want
to do this. I
want to do this.
I want to do
this. I want to
do this. I want
to do this. I
want to do this.
I want to do
this. The old way,
the status quo. And
we say there is
a new, better way.
And then we turn
around and say, look
at the problem. The
old way is causing
you. So for example,
I said, search doesn't
work. It's done. It's
been outdated for years.
No one makes any
money from it. There's
a far better way.
That's got all of
these results. You can
see on the screen
right now. Here's why
search doesn't bring people
back. It's all about
new viewers. How are
you supposed to make
sales? If people only
watch one video that
doesn't happen, that's a
lie. You've been lied
to. And then we
tease the result, but
look what happens when
you do it. You're
going to get a
lot of people who
are going to do
it my way, the
new way. And we
start showing them more
testimonials, right? And just
keep reminding them it
works. So that was
my preferred method for
the emotion brick. It's
literally showing them the
old way doesn't work
and showing proof the
new way does. And
then we move on
to the logic brick.
So this is pretty
simple. We now show
them what the new
way is. So in
the video, we would
have promised I'm going
to show you how
to get some sort
of big result in
the intro. Now we
just show them how
to do it, giving
only the most critical
steps. And at any
point, the steps complex
or the viewers might
be skeptical of its
power, using the motion
brick to simplify that
one bit. And then
just keep reminding them
this works with proof
throughout the video. And
then we get to
your end screen. So
if you're optimizing for
views, if that's your
goal, you want to
push to a previous
version of this video
template if you have
done a deep dive.
Otherwise, just push to
another video that you
think is the next
logical video for them
to watch. Shouldn't be
a very long decision.
If you're optimizing for
sales, push this video
to one of your
high converting sales videos.
If you're optimizing for
emails, push to a
high converting email video.
That's kind of it.
So this is my
script. And what you
can see here is
I'm going to read
it out a little
bit. So have you
ever wondered if the
advice you're following for
growing a channel can
make you money is
wrong? Well, I believe
a lot of it
is and it's holding
you back. In fact,
I know it because
in October 2021, I
quit my business and
I ignored most of
it. And I started
from scratch in three
years generated over 4
million from YouTube using
a system that's not
only work for me,
it's work for countless
others. So we've got
our hook. I then
insert some
new system works. So
tease the result. And
then I'm doing the
setup. So I'm excited
because today I'm going
to give you the
exact blueprint to go
from zero followers to
making a million dollars
on YouTube without worrying
about your subscriber count
because it's not even
a metric we're going
to track. Okay. So
in this deep dive,
you're going to discover
exactly what to focus
on a more awful
outdated advice to ignore.
So you can start
getting results like you
see on screen right
now. See how I'm
teasing the old way.
And then I move
into the proof. So
you're probably wondering, will
this actually work for
me? So this will
work for people who
want to solve a
problem with their channel.
So they make educational
videos that help people
solve a problem of
some source. If you're
an entertainment channel, it's
definitely not the right
system. Feel free to
watch it, but otherwise
I would not do
this. So I'm trying
to put off the
wrong avatar from watching
because I have so
many of them on
my channel. You don't
have to do that.
So how does it
work? I wanted to
test this system. So
I got 40 YouTube
creators in 2023 and
I put them through
it. And on average,
I made 10 K
in the first seven
days of a launch,
but also only two
of them made under
a couple of thousand.
Some people went past
40 K. It was
life -changing. It worked
for you. I'm just
basically, I'm just unpacking
like results, results, results.
And when you're watching
this, it's like, oh
my gosh, he has
got a new way.
So we're just doing
that. Then we come
into the old way
versus new way section.
So let's look at
the transition. So with
that in mind, what's
the strategy we're going
to use to grow
your channel and business
from zero so you
can make a million
dollars? That's my transition.
Well, the first thing
is we're not going
to do it with
affiliate because affiliate basically
means you're putting your
fate in someone else's
hands and a company
can just turn around
and say, we're no
longer giving you commission
and lose all income.
We're not going to
do sponsors. That's great
for entertainment channels, but
not for people who
solve problems. And also
everyone hates working with
them. And we're also
not going to look
at ad revenue because
many of you are
going to be in
niches where that's far
too small to make
it pay off and
worth your while. It's
a great little bonus
because we're able to
hire people to get
your leg up, but
it's not the way
to do this. What
I'm going to do
is show you is
night and day to
what you often get
told to do online.
So you see what
I've done there? I've
just said the old
way, the old way,
the way you've been
told sucks. So let
me ask you a
question. If you wanted
to catch some fish,
would you sit with
a rod and wait
for one? So what
I'm doing now is
I'm bringing in the
emotion brick. So what
I'll do is I'll
label this up and
I'll link to it.
So you can see
the emotion brick, the
steps. And every time
I switch, I won't
read the whole thing
out now. It'll go
on for a while.
I'll probably spell check
it too, because this
is my drivel. But
now let's have a
look at how to
use the template. All
right. So in our
deep dive at the
top, there's some links
so you can check
out my own videos
on it. Here is
the framework we use.
And the first thing
you do is you
set your goal. Like
we do every video.
What do you want?
Sales, views, or emails?
You can't have all
three. It would be
amazing if you can,
and it happens every
now and then, but
just pick one. If
you're a very small
channel, basically it has
to be views, unless
you're just going to
release this as conversion
content and drive other
future videos back at
it. But if you're
an experienced creator, not
advised. Then you're going
to make your thumbnails
and titles. Then you're
going to do your
top three questions that
you think the viewers
are going to want
answers to based on
this packaging. Then you're
going to do your
messy brain dump. So
list every step from
your system to get
a result. Make sure
they'll match or exceed
the expectations. For every
step or claim, find
some sort of proof
that it works. Use
skyscraper bot to research
other videos. You just
want a big plan
here, which is going
to unpack the proof,
the emotion brick, you
know, how you might
get this across the
logic. And then after
that, you're going to
refine it. So start
deleting stuff and just
keep the things that
directly pay off your
three viewers questions. Delete
any steps that are
not critical for getting
a viewer and result,
which is hard. And
then focus heavily on
proving this works. So
you can see I've
got these sections here,
like just plan out
your proof section. Plan
out your emotion brick,
plan out your logic
like this. And in
a dream mode, it's
step one, proof it
works, step two, proof
it works. If you
don't have proof for
every step, don't worry.
But if you can
keep throwing in, it's
good. It needs to
be quick. After that,
we want to be
thinking about what's the
conversion strategy. So if
you picked your goal
as emails, you need
to make sure you've
got your lead magnet
in. You mentioned it
three times, early, mid
and end, and you're
pointing to a high
converting video in the
end screen for emails.
For sales, are you
doing an obvious call
to action or stealth
selling? For this, I
would highly recommend you
do a little bit
of a call to
action. I highly recommend
doing an obvious call
to action towards the
end and then point
to another high converting
sales video. If you're
optimizing for views, don't
have any external calls
to action. Just link
to bingeable videos, point
to a well -received
video that makes sense,
and then move on
to writing or presenting
from bullets. So I
actually presented mine from
bullets, which I know
I've told you not
to do. It took
me six hours to
film and I wouldn't
do it again. It
was exhausting, but I
planned it and practiced
it for a very
long time. So it
worked. So I would
say write it, but
if you're going to
present it for a
long time, it's going
to be a lot
easier. So I would
recommend you do a
call to action. If
you're going to do
a live video, just
keep practicing it over
and over again. I
recorded it, watched it
back, deleted it, recorded
it, watched it back,
and just getting better
and better. And then
upload and add your
tracking links. Now there's
a deep dive guide
here below, which is
just going to keep
you on track. And
then once you've posted
it, we just put
it through our measurement
system. You ask, did
I hit my goal
after seven to 30
days? If so, repeat
the lesson. If you
missed, ask why, avoid
the lesson. And just
remove the emotion from
this and understand that
if we can get
sales, the views on
this doesn't matter. We
can drive it. We
can put emails at
it if we want.
We can put it
as our channel trailer.
We can link every
flipping video to it.
We could even put
some ad revenue behind
it. Although don't go
doing that yet. I
need to do more
investigating on it. So
that is your deep
dive.